

portfolio.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Freecodecamp

19/14-B M C S R s t r e e t,Kumbakonam,Thanjavur,Tamilnadu. vijayponnaiyan93@gmail.com | Mobile: 8760648680

Key Skill: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GitHub, JQuery, SASS, React.js...

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled front-end developer with over **1.8 years** of experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, Bootstrap 5, and JQuery. I am experienced in creating responsive websites and have worked with well-known frameworks like Reactjs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

Frameworks : Bootstrap 4 v 5.

Libraries : React.js, Material, jQuery, Sass.

Dev Tools, Other: Visual Studio Code, Git, Photoshop, Sketch, XAMPP.

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Pepy Technologies

July-2023 - Present

Coimbatore

• Utilize **Bootstrap**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **JavaScript**, **and React.js** for responsive custom website development, ensuring excellent user experience across devices.

• Implement PHP to create dynamic features, enhancing user engagement and functionality. Proficient in **XAMPP for local server** setups, expediting development and ensuring smooth testing.

Front-end DeveloperApr 2022 - June 2023Freelance (Web Developer)Kumbakonam

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Bootstrap
- Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications

UI / UX Designer2019 – 2020MacappStudioChennai

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design intuitive user interfaces for web and mobile applications.
- Conducted user research, created wireframes, and developed interactive prototypes using tools like **Adobe XD and Photo shop, Sketch**.

EDUCATION

Mahendra Engineering College, Anna University

B.E.- Aeronautical Engineering

Namakkal, Tamilnadu- 637503 2014 – 2017

PROJECTS

Projects 1

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Git, and XAMPP.

Checkout

• VFX and Website Development: Make a special skills section highlighting your knowledge of website development technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, Bootstrap 5 ,jQuery. as well as VFX tools specify particular tools.

Projects 2 HTML5,CSS3,JavaScript,Bootstrap,jQuery,Git,XAMPP. Checkout

• Extensive experience creating websites in the fast-paced environment of an **IT tech and BPO organisation**. We used these technologies to develop aesthetically pleasing, responsive websites that meet customer specifications.

Projects 2 HTML5,CSS3,JavaScript,Bootstrap,jQuery,Git, XAMPP. Checkout

• Handled frontend development projects for NS Automations, a well-known **manufacturer of industrial and electronics products**. developed user-friendly interfaces that promote smooth interaction and functionality for a variety of industrial automation applications.